HANCE KING

gnikchance@gmail.com · https://gnikchance.github.io

Professional Summary

Passionate and effective full-stack developer with over 5 years of experience in producing enterprise-level web and mobile applications.

Key skills include: constructing NodeJS/Express API endpoints, implementing front-end Javascript (Vue & React) designs, and building SQL statements using PostgreSQL and SQL Developer.

EDUCATION

Florida State University

BS Information & Communication Technology

Tallahassee, Fl. 2012 - 2016

EXPERIENCE

Florida State University

Software Developer

Remote 2018 - Present

- Created RESTful API's using NodeJS and Express for custom web applications
- Built SQL queries that powered data-driven apps and their front end consumption
- Oversaw official myFSU mobile app development and maintenance
- Managed web portal application for 40,000+ daily users

FSU Alumni Association.

Webmaster

Tallahassee, Fl. 2016 - 2018

- Developed web applications using Express, VueJS, and PostgreSQL
- Designed and managed primary website using Drupal CMS
- Led and supervised a team of web and digital communication interns
- Ran consistent e-mail campaigns to over 200,000 constituents

Student Opportunity Center.

Full-Stack Intern

Tallahassee, Fl. 2014 - 2016

- Updated databases using mySQL & MongoDB
- Designed landing page and web application using Bootstrap
- Managed all social media accounts and automated email responses
- Worked with CEO to implement funding strategies

SKILLS

Languages & Libraries: Tools & Platforms:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, VueJS, NodeJS, C#, Java, Bootstrap, Bulma, SQL Unity, Virtual Reality, MongoDB/Atlas, Photoshop, Command Line (CLI)

PROJECTS

Spicy Writer NodeJS, AJAX, Bulma, Express

https://www.spicywriter.com

Light-hearted web app that turns "boring" words into "spicy" ones

VR Web Games Express, VueJS, ThreeJS, A-Frame Central hub and directory for browser-based VR games https://www.vrwebgames.com

Cocktail Champ VueJS, 3rd Party API, NodeJS Single-page application for discovering drink recipes

https://cocktailchamp.herokuapp.com/

VR Browser Demo Javascript, ThreeJS, A-Frame

https://gnikchance.github.io/vrDemo

Browser-based VR demo, compatible with any VR headset